A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller Gubernatorial records, New York Office, Series 22 FA365
Rockefeller Archive Center
- George Hinman and Ilene Slater Files, 1959-1962; 4; 6 Cubic Feet
  - Subject Files - McMicking, Joseph R. (Box 50, Folder 1208)
    California
  - Subject Files - Memoranda - Hinman-O'Donnell Memos (Box 50, Folder 1209)
  - Subject Files - Memoranda - L. Judson Morhouse (Box 50, Folder 1210)
  - Subject Files - Memoranda - Root, Oren (Box 50, Folder 1211)
  - Subject Files - Miscellaneous - Conventions and Elections (Box 50, Folder 1212)
  - Subject Files - Miscellaneous - Meeting Notes, Schedules, Memoranda (Box 50, Folder 1213)
  - Subject Files - Newspapers - Correspondence (Box 50, Folder 1214)
  - Subject Files - Newspapers - Reactions to NAR Statements (Box 50, Folder 1215)
  - Subject Files - "New York State Citizens for Nixon and Lodge" (Box 50, Folder 1216)
  - Subject Files - Nixon, Richard M., 1959-1960 (Box 51, Folder 1217)
  - Subject Files - O'Donnell, Harry (Box 51, Folder 1218)
    New York State Republican State Committee
  - Subject Files - Ogden, Al (Box 51, Folder 1219)
    New York, pro-NAR
  - Subject Files - "People for Rockefeller" (Box 51, Folder 1220)
    Mailing list
  - Subject Files - Political News Summary, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 1221)
  - Subject Files - Polls - General (Box 51, Folder 1222)
  - Subject Files - Polls - Princeton (Box 52, Folder 1223)
  - Subject Files - Position Papers Issue Analysis (Box 52, Folder 1224)
  - Subject Files - Presidential Appointees Committee (Box 52, Folder 1225)
  - Subject Files - "Presidential Preview" (Box 52, Folder 1226)
    National Convention Newsletter covering the major political parties
  - Subject Files - Public Relations (Box 52, Folder 1227)
  - Subject Files - Reappropriation (Box 52, Folder 1228)
  - Subject Files - Reports (Box 52, Folder 1229)
  - Subject Files - Republican Party - New York State Republican Committee (Box 52, Folder 1229)
  - Subject Files - Republican Party - Republican National Committee, 1959-1960 (Box 52, Folder 1231)
  - Subject Files - Rockefeller, Nelson A. - Speeches (Box 52, Folder 1232)
  - Subject Files - Rockefeller, Nelson A. - Statements and Clippings Regarding Candidacy (Box 52, Folder 1233)
  - Subject Files - Rockefeller, Nelson A. - Statements and Clippings Regarding Candidacy (Box 52, Folder 1234)
    May 15, 1960, decision not to accept Vice Presidential nomination or draft
  - Subject Files - Rockefeller, Nelson A. - Statements and Clippings Regarding Candidacy (Box 52, Folder 1235)
    December 26, 1959, decision not to run for president
  - Subject Files - Shattuck, Edward (Box 52, Folder 1236)
    California Republican National Committee Member
  - Subject Files - Sivertsen, Wilma (Box 52, Folder 1237)
    New York State Republican State Committee Vice-Chairman
  - Subject Files - Stassen, Harold F. (Box 52, Folder 1238)
    Pennsylvania
  - Subject Files - Television Exposure Plans (Box 52, Folder 1239)
  - Subject Files - West Coast Trip, George L. Hinman Folder (Box 53, Folder 1240)
  - Subject Files - 1960 Republican Convention - Delegate Information (Box 53, Folder 1241)
  - Subject Files - 1960 Republican Convention - List of Delegates, 1956 (Box 53, Folder 1242)
  - NOT USED (Box 53, Folder 1243)
  - Subject Files - 1960 Republican Convention - Miscellaneous (Box 53, Folder 1244)
  - Subject Files - 1960 Republican Convention - Notes on Delegate Selection, 1952 (Box 53, Folder 1245)
  - Subject Files - 1960 Republican Convention - Platform Committee, 1960 (Box 53, Folder 1246)
  - Subject Files - 1960 Republican Convention - Rough Notes, George L. Hinman (Box 53, Folder 1247)
  - Subject Files - 1960 Republican Convention - Schedules (Box 53, Folder 1248)
  - Subject Files - 1960 Republican Convention - Speeches (Box 54, Folder 1249)
    NAR's handwritten copy of his speech introducing Richard M. Nixon as presidential nominee; printed booklet of major speeches delivered at the convention
  - George Hinman's Talent File (Box 57, Folder 1315)
- Rockefeller for President Citizens Information Center, 1958-1960; 5; 1.6 Cubic Feet
  Subseries 5 is divided into three sections: General Files, State Files, and Card Files. General Files and State Files are arranged alphabetically. Card Files are arranged alphabetically by state.
  These are the files of Alexander Halpern, chairman of the Rockefeller for President Citizens Information Center, a private group that sought to promote Governor Rockefeller's candidacy for president in 1960. The CIC, as it was called, acted as a distribution center for information about Governor Rockefeller. It was established in response to requests for information about Rockefeller from independent groups around the country which were seeking the Republican nomination for him. The CIC was conceived in the summer of 1959 by a group of Governor Rockefeller's friends and supporters. This group included R. Burdell Bixby, George L. Hinman, L. Judson Morehouse, Roswell B. Perkins, Oren Root, Oscar M. Ruebhausen, and Mr. Halpern. It was formally organized in September 1959, and an office was opened in the Belmont Plaza Hotel on Lexington Avenue, New York, in October. The CIC ceased operation on December 28, 1959, two days after Governor Rockefeller announced that he would not seek the nomination. At that time Mr. Halpern requested that other Rockefeller for President Committees throughout the country also cease activities. Nevertheless, throughout most of 1960 letters continued to arrive from individuals urging Governor Rockefeller to run for president.
  The General Files contain office memoranda; correspondence; and lists of volunteers and of "Rockefeller for President" organizations. The State Files consist of correspondence with individuals from various states. The Card Files consist of approximately 800 4" x 6" blue and white index cards arranged by state. The cards contain addresses of political organizations, citizens groups, campaign volunteers, and abstracts of polls taken by independent organizations. The cards can also be used to locate correspondence with individuals filed in the State Files of this subseries.
  - General Files - "Birth and Death Notices" (Box 54, Folder 1250)
  - General Files - Budgets (Box 54, Folder 1251)
  - General Files - Correspondence - College Groups for Rockefeller (Box 54, Folder 1252)
  - General Files - Correspondence - Negative Letters Received (Box 54, Folder 1253)
  - General Files - Correspondence - Special Appeal Letters, New York File (Box 54, Folder 1254)
  - General Files - Form Letters (Box 54, Folder 1255)
  - General Files - Lists - Miscellaneous (Box 54, Folder 1256)
  - General Files - Lists - Proposal for National Committee (Box 54, Folder 1257)
  - General Files - Lists - Volunteers (Box 54, Folder 1258)
  - General Files - Organization and Procedures (Box 54, Folder 1259)
  - General Files - Publicity and Promotion (Box 54, Folder 1260)
  - General Files - Stationery (Box 54, Folder 1261)
  - State Files - Alabama (Box 54, Folder 1262)
  - State Files - Alaska (Box 54, Folder 1263)
  - State Files - Arizona (Box 54, Folder 1264)
  - State Files - Akansas (Box 54, Folder 1265)
  - State Files - California (Box 54, Folder 1266)
  - State Files - California (Box 54, Folder 1267)
  - State Files - Colorado (Box 55, Folder 1268)
  - State Files - Connecticut (Box 55, Folder 1269)
  - State Files - District of Columbia (Box 55, Folder 1270)
  - State Files - Florida (Box 55, Folder 1271)
  - State Files - Georgia (Box 55, Folder 1272)
  - State Files - Hawaii (Box 55, Folder 1273)
  - State Files - Idaho (Box 55, Folder 1274)
  - State Files - Illinois (Box 55, Folder 1275)
  - State Files - Indiana (Box 55, Folder 1276)
  - State Files - Iowa (Box 55, Folder 1277)
  - State Files - Kansas (Box 55, Folder 1278)
  - State Files - Kentucky (Box 55, Folder 1279)
  - State Files - Louisiana (Box 55, Folder 1280)
  - State Files - Maine (Box 55, Folder 1281)
  - State Files - Maryland (Box 55, Folder 1282)
  - State Files - Montana (Box 55, Folder 1283)
  - State Files - Nebraska (Box 55, Folder 1284)
  - State Files - Nevada (Box 55, Folder 1285)
  - State Files - New Hampshire (Box 55, Folder 1286)
  - State Files - Massachusetts (Box 55, Folder 1287)
  - State Files - Michigan (Box 55, Folder 1288)
  - State Files - Minnesota (Box 55, Folder 1289)
  - State Files - Mississippi (Box 55, Folder 1290)
  - State Files - Missouri (Box 55, Folder 1291)
  - State Files - New Jersey (Box 55, Folder 1292)
  - State Files - New Mexico (Box 55, Folder 1293)
  - State Files - New York, 1959 (Box 56, Folder 1294)
  - State Files - New York, 1960 (Box 56, Folder 1295)
  - State Files - North Carolina (Box 56, Folder 1296)
  - State Files - North Dakota (Box 56, Folder 1297)
  - State Files - Ohio (Box 56, Folder 1298)
  - State Files - Oklahoma (Box 56, Folder 1299)
  - State Files - Oregon (Box 56, Folder 1300)
  - State Files - Pennsylvania (Box 56, Folder 1301)
  - State Files - Rhode Island (Box 56, Folder 1302)
  - State Files - South Carolina (Box 56, Folder 1303)
  - State Files - South Dakota (Box 56, Folder 1304)
  - State Files - Tennessee (Box 56, Folder 1305)
  - State Files - Texas (Box 56, Folder 1306)
  - State Files - Utah (Box 56, Folder 1307)
  - State Files - Vermont (Box 56, Folder 1308)
  - State Files - Virginia (Box 56, Folder 1309)
  - State Files - Washington (Box 56, Folder 1310)
  - State Files - West Virgina (Box 56, Folder 1311)
  - State Files - Wisconsin (Box 56, Folder 1312)
  - State Files - Wyoming (Box 56, Folder 1313)
  - State Files - Miscellaneous Foreign, Lebanon (Box 56, Folder 1314)
  - Card File (Box 57, Folder 1316)